{
    "user": {
        "user_name": "Mr. Skaggs",
        "session_length": 10
    },
    "books": [
        {
            "title": "Phillip K. Dick",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-27",
                    "quote": "Reality is that which, when you stop believing in it, doesn't go away.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Anais Nin",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-22",
                    "quote": "Life shrinks or expands in proportion to one\u2019s courage.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Predictably Wrong, E.Y.",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "front": "Instrumental Rationality",
                    "back": "systematically achieving your values.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-01",
                    "front": "Epistemic Rationality",
                    "back": "systematically improving the accuracy of your beliefs.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Noticing Confusion, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-01",
                    "front": "What is Evidence?",
                    "back": "- For an event to be\u00a0evidence about\u00a0a target of inquiry, it has to happen\u00a0differently\u00a0in a way that\u2019s entangled with the\u00a0different\u00a0possible states of the target.\n- More technically, there has to be Shannon mutual information between the evidential event and the target of inquiry, relative to your current state of uncertainty about both of them.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Stuart Russel",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "front": "You can't get the coffee if you're dead",
                    "back": "description of why almost any agent goal implies an instrumental strategy of surviving / not being shut down",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Deep Learning, Goodfellow and Bengio",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-27",
                    "front": "\"Fire together, wire together\"",
                    "back": "Hebbian Learning rule",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Wikipedia",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-22",
                    "front": "Shannon information",
                    "back": "I(x) = log(p(x))",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-01",
                    "front": "Shannon entropy",
                    "back": "H = E[ I(x) ]",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Never Split the Difference by Chris Voss",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-08",
                    "front": "There are 3 kinds of yes:",
                    "back": "- Counterfeit\n- Confirmation\n- Commitment",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "front": "Normative leverage",
                    "back": "when you find inconsistencies in your opponents words and actions. Nobody likes to be a hypocrite find out what your counterparts usual behavior.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "front": "Mirroring",
                    "back": "the concept of \"birds of a feather flock together.\" You send subtle signals that you're similar to your counterpart and should be bonding with. Seen often body language. Vos' recommendation: Repeat the last three words of what the person just said",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "note": "Your mindset should be that of discovery. Learn as much about the situation as possible",
                    "type": "note"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-28",
                    "front": "There are three types of negotiators:",
                    "back": "- Assertives\n- Accommodaters\n- Analysts",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "front": "Negative leverage",
                    "back": "When you control something your counterpart wishes to avoid",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "front": "Analysts",
                    "back": " super high trait C. They prepare a lot and are very calculating but beware that you're not offputting by how cold you are. Hypersensitive to reciprocity. Highly introverted. Use data and reason with them. Not quick to answer calibrated questions",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "front": "Labeling",
                    "back": "a type of tactical empathy; understanding your opponents emotions, articulating them, and respectfully verbalizing",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "quote": "Assumptions blind, hypotheses guide.",
                    "type": "quote"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-28",
                    "note": "Use your opponent's deadlines against them. Cars salesman are more likely to give good deals at end of the month, businessmen at end of the financial quarter.",
                    "type": "note"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "front": "The 7/38/55 rule",
                    "back": "7% of what we communicate is done so through the verbal word, 35% is through the tone and intonation, and 55% is through our body language.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "front": "Assertive",
                    "back": "time is money. Perfection not necessary. Winning is the goal. Prioritization of respect. Must be heard. Tell not ask. Every silence is an opportunity to speak more. If you're dealing with this type, mirrors and calibrated questions are both excellent options. Look for the that's right",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "note": "Avoid anchoring (giving the first offer) in monetary bargaining. But beware of sharks who will give a ludicrous anchor to throw you off.",
                    "type": "note"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "note": "Who has control in a negotiation the talker or the listener? The listener of course. That's because the talker is revealing information.",
                    "type": "note"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "note": "In general, *that's right* is what you're looking for. It signals your counterpart believes they've come up with the solution themselves. Alternatively, *you're right* is bad and often dismissive.",
                    "type": "note"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "note": "Voss asks the same open ended questions until they get frustrated and give up",
                    "type": "note"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "front": "Thesis",
                    "back": "That negotiation is an exercise in tactical empathy and honing those skills can improve your life.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "front": "Accusation audit",
                    "back": "identifying all the reaso's you counterpart might be angry with you.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "front": "The three voices you should use when negotiating:",
                    "back": "The FM DJ voice: a self-assured voice of calm and reason, use it calm down your counterpart\nA positive playful voice: Use most of the time, encourages positivity and cooperation\nAn assertive dominant voice: Use with caution",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "front": "Accomadators",
                    "back": "high trait A. Very friendly. Be friendly with them. They might leave out objections or problem areas to avoid conflict",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-28",
                    "front": "Blackswan events",
                    "back": "Sudden surprising information which changes the balance of leverage in a negotiation",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "front": "Positive leverage",
                    "back": "when you can provide something that your counterpart desires",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "note": "In a job interview or salary negotiation, ask \"what does it take to be successful here.\" That'll give the boss a personal stake in your success. You've just created an unofficial mentor",
                    "type": "note"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-02",
                    "note": "Good negotiator know they need to be ready for surprises. Great negotiators use their skills to reveal the surprises they're certain exist.",
                    "type": "note"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "note": "The FBI developed their negotiation methods through iteration while having intense skin in the game.Harvard intellectuals did so through theory. Consequently, the FBI methods were superior.",
                    "type": "note"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Odds and Ends, JW",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 2,
                    "date": "2021-01-19",
                    "front": "68-95-99 Rule",
                    "back": "If X is distributed normally, then:\n- 68% of time within \u03bc\u00b1\u03c3\n- 95% of time within \u03bc\u00b12\u03c3\n- 99% of time within \u03bc\u00b13\u03c3",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Wikipedia",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "front": "Statistical model",
                    "back": "A pair (S, P) where S is the set of possible observations and P is the set of probability distributions on S. P is almost always parameterized by some set of hyperparameters { \\theta \\member \\Theta }.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "front": "Likelihood function",
                    "back": "measures the\u00a0goodness of fit\u00a0of a\u00a0statistical model\u00a0to a\u00a0sample of data\u00a0for given values of the unknown\u00a0parameters.\n",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Predictably Wrong, Eliezer Yudkowsky\n",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-19",
                    "front": "deontological",
                    "back": "the study of the nature of duty and obligation",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-27",
                    "front": "absurdity bias",
                    "back": "events that have never happened are not recalled, and hence deemed to have probability zero.\nWhen no flooding has recently occurred (and yet the probabilities are still fairly calculable), people refuse to buy flood insurance even when it is heavily subsidized and priced far below an actuarially fair value.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-27",
                    "front": "The conjunction fallacy",
                    "back": "- when humans assign a higher probability to a proposition of the form \u201cA and B\u201d than to one of the propositions \u201cA\u201d or \u201cB\u201d in isolation\n- \u201csubstitute judgment of representativeness for judgment of probability.\n- \u201cEx. End diplomatic relations w/ USSR +- invasion of Poland.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Noticing Confusion, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-19",
                    "quote": "Absence of proof is not proof of absence.\nIn probability theory, absence of evidence is evidence of absence.",
                    "type": "quote"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-19",
                    "front": "Truth bias",
                    "back": "People are more likely to believe the truth then to express disbelief in a lie.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-19",
                    "front": "The effects of likelihood ratios on probability ratios",
                    "back": "When we see evidence, hypotheses that assigned a higher likelihood to that evidence gain probability, at the expense of hypotheses that assigned a lower likelihood to the evidence.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "The Puzzle of Motivation - Dan Pink",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "3 Intrinsic Motivators",
                    "back": "Autonomy\nPurpose \nMastery",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Fake Beliefs, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "front": "Belief in belief",
                    "back": "Claimant anticipates as if their belief is false, but makes excuses as if they believed in the belief.\nEx. Invisible dragon in the garage, little kids and Santa Clause, Draco and Pureblood eugenics.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "HPMOR, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-19",
                    "quote": "Hesitation is always easy, but rarely useful.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "HPMOR, Eliezer Yudkowsky",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "quote": "If you can't criticise, you can't optimise.",
                    "type": "quote"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "quote": "I hope you don't mind if I test that - it's not that I don't believe you, but as the saying goes, 'Trust, but verify'.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Predictably Wrong, Eliezer Yudkowsky",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-27",
                    "front": "base rate neglect",
                    "back": "grounding one\u2019s judgments in how well sets of characteristics feel like they fit together, and neglecting how common each characteristic is in the population at large.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-19",
                    "front": "Scope Insensitivity",
                    "back": "a cognitive bias that occurs when the valuation of a problem is not valued with a multiplicative relationship to its size; a particular kind of extension neglect.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "front": "availability heuristic",
                    "back": "judging the frequency or probability of an event by the ease with which examples of the event come to mind.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "front": "Extension neglect",
                    "back": "type of cognitive bias which occurs when the sample size is ignored while evaluating a study in which the sample size is logically relevant.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Wikipedia",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-01",
                    "front": "Mutual information",
                    "back": "- A measure of the mutual dependence between two random variables.\n- I(X; Y) = D_KL(P_XY || P_X x P_Y)",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-01",
                    "front": "Kullback-Leibler Divergence",
                    "back": "- (also called relative entropy) \n- a measure of how one probability distribution is different from a second, reference probability distribution\n- Sum(P(x) * log (P(x) / Q(x)))\n- H(P, Q) - H(P)",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Lao Tzu",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "quote": "Nature does not hurry, yet everything is accomplished.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Khan Academy",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "front": "Confidence interval",
                    "back": "the largest p-value we accept before rejecting the null hypothesis.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Odds and Ends, Weisberg",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 3,
                    "date": "2021-01-21",
                    "front": "Valid",
                    "back": "An argument such that the conclusion must be true if the premises are true",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "Common Types of Inductive Arguments",
                    "back": "- Generalizing from observed instances\n- Use what we know about a general population to draw conclusions about particular instances\n- Inference to the best explanation is another common form of argument\n",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "Sound",
                    "back": "Argument is valid and rests on true premises",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "quote": "Deductive logic is the branch of logic that studies what follows with certainty. Inductive logic deals with uncertainty, things that only follow with high probability.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "JFK",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "quote": "The hottest place in Hell is reserved for those who in time of crisis remain neutral.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Wikipedia",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-01",
                    "front": "Newcomb's paradox",
                    "back": "Box A is clear, and always contains a visible $1,000.\nBox B is opaque, and its content has already been set by the predictor:\nIf the predictor has predicted the player will take both boxes A and B, then box B contains nothing.\nIf the predictor has predicted that the player will take only box B, then box B contains $1,000,000.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Isaac Asimov",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "front": "Asimov's 3 Laws",
                    "back": "First Law\n- A robot may not injure a human being or, through inaction, allow a human being to come to harm.\nSecond Law\n- A robot must obey the orders given it by human beings except where such orders would conflict with the First Law.\nThird Law\n- A robot must protect its own existence as long as such protection does not conflict with the First or Second Law",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "HPMOR, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 3,
                    "date": "2021-01-21",
                    "quote": "Only a man exceedingly proud and vain would believe that his heir should be like himself, rather than like who he wished that he could be.\n",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Wikipedia",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-01",
                    "front": "Monte Carlo methods",
                    "back": "a broad class of computational algorithms that rely on repeated random sampling to obtain numerical results. The underlying concept is to use randomness to solve problems that might be deterministic in principle.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Change Your Mind, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "2 Ways to Questions with the False Dilemma Fallacy",
                    "back": "- If I saw that there was a superior alternative to my current policy, would I be glad in the depths of my heart, or would I feel a tiny flash of reluctance before I let go?\n- Did I spend five minutes with my eyes closed, brainstorming wild and creative options, trying to think of a better alternative?",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "Fallacy of the Grey",
                    "back": "Because nothing's black and white, there exist only equally grey things",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "Disconfirmation bias",
                    "back": "the tendency for people to extend critical scrutiny to information which contradicts their prior beliefs and accept uncritically information that is congruent with their prior beliefs.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "Humility",
                    "back": "- To take specific actions in anticipation of your own errors.\n- To confess your fallibility and then do nothing about it is not humble; it is boasting of your modesty.\u201d\n",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "Tsuyoku naritai!",
                    "back": "I'll always run as fast as I can",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Grapes of Wrath, Steinbeck",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-27",
                    "quote": "For anybody else it was a mistake, but if you think it was a sin-then it's a sin. A fella builds his own sins right up from the groun.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Friedrich Nietzsche",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-27",
                    "quote": "There is more wisdom in your body than in your deepest philosophy.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "George Hotz",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-23",
                    "quote": "You are bytes in God's computer.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Phil Karlton",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-23",
                    "quote": "There are only two hard things in Computer Science: cache invalidation and naming things.",
                    "type": "quote"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-23",
                    "quote": "There are 2 hard problems in computer science: cache invalidation, naming things, and off-by-1 errors.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Eleanor Roosevelt",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-05",
                    "quote": "The future belongs to those who believe in the beauty of their dreams.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Mysterious Questions, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "quote": "When you contain the source of a thought, it becomes truly a part of you and grows along with you.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Noticing Confusion, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-19",
                    "front": "Conservation of Expected Evidence",
                    "back": "- The expectation of the posterior probability, after viewing the evidence, must equal the prior probability.\n- P(H) = P(E) P(H|E) + P(~E) P(H|~E)\n- 0 = (P(H|E)-P(H))P(E) + (P(H|~E)-P(H))P(~E)",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "HPMOR, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "quote": "Your strength as a rationalist is your ability to be more confused by fiction than by reality.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Master Oogway",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-05",
                    "quote": "Yesterday is history,\ntomorrow is a mystery,\nand today is a gift...\nthat's why they call it the present",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Odds and Ends, JW",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 3,
                    "date": "2021-01-21",
                    "front": "The Sure-thing Principle",
                    "back": "If you would choose  X  over  Y  if you knew that  E  was true, and you\u2019d also choose  X  over  Y  if you knew  E  wasn\u2019t true, then you should choose  X  over  Y  when you don\u2019t know whether  E  is true or not",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 3,
                    "date": "2021-01-21",
                    "front": "Gambler's Fallacy",
                    "back": "Thinking you're due for a change in luck despite events being independent",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 3,
                    "date": "2021-01-21",
                    "front": "Fair",
                    "back": "Unbiased and Independent",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Mysterious Answers, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "Publication bias",
                    "back": "the outcome of an experiment or research study influences the decision whether to publish or otherwise distribute it.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "Confirmation bias",
                    "back": "The tendency to search for, interpret, favor, and recall information in a way that confirms or supports one's prior beliefs or values",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "Mysterious answer",
                    "back": "A blanket answer to a hard question which is a curiosity-stopper instead of an anticipation-controller. Even after the answer is given the question still remains a mystery.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "Semantic stopsign",
                    "back": "Not a propositional assertion, so much as a cognitive traffic signal: do not think past this point.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Noticing Confusion, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-22",
                    "front": "Illusion of transparency",
                    "back": "- A cognitive bias in which you assume people will understand your attempts at communication (writing, speech, etc.) because you know what you're saying\n- Related to hindsight bias",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-22",
                    "front": "Expecting short inferential distances",
                    "back": "In our ancestral environment, you were unlikely to end up more than one inferential step away from anyone else. Anyone who says something with no obvious support is a liar or an idiot. Conversely, if you say something blatantly obvious and the other person doesn\u2019t see it, they\u2019re the idiot, or they\u2019re being deliberately obstinate to annoy you.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-22",
                    "front": "Hindsight bias",
                    "back": "- the I-knew-it-all-along phenomenon\n- Subjects who know the actual answer to a question assign much higher probabilities they \u201cwould have\u201d guessed for that answer, compared to subjects who must guess without knowing the answer.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Harry Potter, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "front": "faux pas",
                    "back": "- an embarrassing or tactless act or remark in a social situation.\n- French, literally \u2018false step\u2019.",
                    "type": "flash"
                },
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-19",
                    "quote": "We become what we are meant to be by following our desires wherever they lead. That is the insight of Salazar.",
                    "type": "quote"
                },
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "front": "planning fallacy",
                    "back": "a phenomenon in which predictions about how much time will be needed to complete a future task display an optimism bias and underestimate the time needed.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Merrian Webster",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "front": "null hypothes",
                    "back": "the hypothesis that an observed difference (as between the means of two samples) is due to chance alone and not due to a systematic cause",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "P.C. Hodgell",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-29",
                    "quote": "That which can be destroyed by the truth should be.",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Wikipedia",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-02-01",
                    "front": "Cross Entropy",
                    "back": "- measures the average number of bits needed to identify an event drawn from the set if a coding scheme used for the set is optimized for an estimated probability distribution q, rather than the true distribution p.\n- H(p, q) = - E_p [log q]",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "HPMOR, EY",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 4,
                    "date": "2021-01-25",
                    "front": "Fundamental attribution error (aka Correspondance bias)",
                    "back": "When evaluating other people, we tend to explain their behaviour as fundamental personality traits instead of consequences of their recent experiences (eg someone just yelled at them). This is because we don't see what they've been through before encountering them",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Eliezer Yudkowski",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "quote": "Harry sent his parents a glare. \"I am a conscientious objector to child conscription, on grounds that I should not have to suffer for a disintegrating school system's failure to provide teachers or study materials of even minimally adequate quality.\"",
                    "type": "quote"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Wikipedia",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 5,
                    "date": "2021-01-26",
                    "front": "Simulated annealing",
                    "back": "- a probabilistic technique for approximating the global optimum of a given function.\n- Name comes from annealing in metallurgy, a technique involving heating and controlled cooling of a material to increase the size of its crystals and reduce their defects.\n- Slow cooling = slow decrease in the probability of accepting worse solutions as the solution space is explored.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "title": "Wikipedia",
            "cards": [
                {
                    "level": 2,
                    "date": "2021-01-19",
                    "front": "p-value",
                    "back": "the probability of obtaining test results at least as extreme as the results actually observed, under the assumption that the null hypothesis is correct.",
                    "type": "flash"
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}
